

CAREER SUMMARY:

A highly competent and organized **Senior Customer Support Engineer** with 7+ years experience in software procurement, installation, administration & compatibility. Possesses a proven ability to assist with the day-to-day running of an IT department and its business IT systems. Extensive knowledge of monitoring and controlling data security within guidelines to ensure compliance and report on possible improvements. Well mannered, articulate and able to act as a point of contact for colleagues and external clients.

PERSONAL INFORMATION:

Name : B SUNIL KUMAR
Date of Birth : 11-Mar-1987

Present Address: Plot No. 7A, Manikkam Nagar, Madambakkam, Chennai - 600 126

Mobile& E-Mail: +91-9567010124 (India) & sunilkumar edp@hotmail.com

EDUCATION:

2007 - 2010 Bachelor of Engineering (B.E), Electronics and Communication

JRN Rajasthan Vidyapeeth University, India

2002 - 2005 Diploma in Electronics and Communication Engineering (DECE)

Scad Gramodhaya Polytechnic College, Cheranmahadevi, Tamilnadu, India

CERTIFICATION:

Microsoft Certified IT Professional

Certification ID: 8506170

Microsoft Cloud Fundamentals: Explore Cloud Services.

TECHNOLOGY SUMMARY:

Operating System : Windows 7 /8 &10, Linux and Ubuntu

Windows Server 2003/2008/2012

Software : Microsoft Office 2003/2007/2010/2016/O365

Cloud Technology : AWS Cloud Computing, Google Cloud Platform.

Antivirus : Symantec/ Trend Micro Enterprise Suite / MacAfee Antivirus,

Hardware : Watch Guard Firebox firewall/ Desktop / Laptop

Servers : IBM X-Series Server, Dell Power Edge T410

Protocol Services : TCP/IP, HTTP, HTTPS, FTP, SFTP, DNS, DHCP & WINS

Others : Microsoft 2008 & 2012 and 2016Active Directory, Microsoft Exchange 2003

& 2007,

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dates (from – to) Mar 2018 – Dec 2021

• Name and address of employer Manpower Group Services India Pvt. Ltd.

• Occupation or position held Support Engineer.

• Onsite Engineer Nissan Digital India LLP

• Main activities and responsibilities

1) Experience in Zoho service desk and SysAid tickets tools.

- Coordinated with Level 1&2 technical support specialists to take over calls outside their level of support.
- 3) Assisted customers with more difficult technical issues requiring a greater level of personalized care and in greater length.
- 4) Escalated support desk tickets to Level 3 in the most crucial circumstances and after considerable time had been spent on a single ticket.
- 5) Escalated help desk tickets to Level 2 / Tier 2 support when outside the scope of L1/T1 technician support.
- 6) Onboarded and trained all incoming junior tech support specialists.
- 7) Trained and assisted users with policies and procedures for PDA, mobile computing, and video conferencing systems.
- 8) Responsible for preparing the audio/visual for all-hands and executive meetings.
- 9) Assigned, configured, and maintained the IP and conference phones.
- 10) SCCM client Installation and troubleshooting.
- 11) SCCM 2012 troubleshooting and Fixing OS Deploying issues with the help of the imaging team.
- 12) Active directory 2012 create User, OU and Computers and applying Group Policy for ODC.
- 13) Co-ordinate with onshore support/cross-functional teams to deliver IT services for customers.
- 14) Monthly Windows Patching on Dev Servers.
- 15) Implemented Network using TCP/IP and Network Printers and Faxes.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dates (from – to) Oct 2017 – Feb 2018

• Name and address of employer Quadsel Systems Pvt Ltd.

• Occupation or position held Senior Customer Support Engineer.

• Onsite Engineer Renault Nissan Technology & Business Center India Private Limited.

• Main activities and responsibilities

16) Experience in HP service manager tickets tools.

- 17) Manage the issues remotely or with the assistance of the IT support
- 18) Configuration and Troubleshooting Mail clients like MS Outlook and Outlook Express.
- 19) Creating the AD users and objects and resetting the password through the AD link.
- 20) Troubleshooting VPN access related issues.
- 21) Troubleshooting of Network connectivity issues.
- 22) Group Policy related issues/ GPO permission issues.
- 23) Managing and Maintaining VoIP devices.
- 24) Manage local issues on site.
- 25) Supporting various types of desktop and laptop issues.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Dates (from – to) Nov 2014 – Aug 2017

• Name and address of employer Ensure Support India Limited (REDINGTON)

• Occupation or position held Senior Customer Support Engineer (Team Leader)

• Onsite Engineer Olam Information Services, Chennai.

• Main activities and responsibilities

- 1) Systems administration, maintenance and monitoring of various day-to-day operations.
- 2) Technical support to clients via email and chat remote support.
- 3) Handling all troubleshooting and implementation of new setup at client premises.
- 4) Knowledge of file & print services.
- 5) Service Pack/ Hotfix/ Software Installation Issues & Troubleshooting analyzing service pack. Log & Windows update. Log
- 6) User Rights Assignment, Service not started related issues.
- 7) Troubleshooting the Ms Outlook and Lync related issues.
- 8) Vendor Coordination for Hardware Replacements.
- 9) Experience in SysAid tickets tools.
- 10) Supporting Hardware and Software issues.
- 11) Lead a team of 15 member L1 Support Engineers in providing technical support & services for Remote Access.

• Dates (from – to) Dec 2011 - Jul 2014

• Name and address of employer Prince Gardens, Coimbatore, Tamilnadu, India

Occupation or position held
 Systems Administrator

• Main activities and responsibilities

1) Plan, Organize, Direct, Control and Evaluate the operations of information systems and electronic data processing (EDP)

- 2) Troubleshoot hardware, software and network operating system.
- 3) Installing and configuring ADS on Windows 2000, 2003 & 2008 servers.
- 4) Creating users, groups and assigning permissions as per requirements.
- 5) Creating backup and recovery policy, performing data backups.
- 6) Responsible for documentation of asset.
- 7) Provide individual training and support based on request.
- 8) Knowledge of Network concepts.
- 9) Load all required software.
- 10) Monitor the security of all technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- 1) Computer hardware and software systems and programs.
- 2) Computer troubleshooting & Computer viruses and security.
- 3) Email and internet programs & Ability to install and administer computer hardware, software and networks.

STRENGTHS:

- 1) Excellent problem solving and time management skills
- 2) Self-motivated and highly organized & Positive attitude & Self-motivation.
- 3) Good ability to plan & Sincere and hard working.
- 4) Adaptability to different environments and Team Work.

LANGUAGES KNOWN:

Tamil, English, Malayalam

DECLARATION

I, Sunil Kumar, hereby declare that the above-mentioned details furnished by me are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place : Madambakkam, Chennai Yours faithfully,

Date :

(B Sunil Kumar)